Diver Diamond

diamond.oliver@gmail.com | 07846 394 258

I am a full-stack developer, passionate about: ES6, Lisps & functional programming; Linux architecture; and approaches that emphasise devops, fast delivery, clean code, & developer anarchy.

Last Position: HSBC Digital Transformation Team

Physics, 2:1, Imperial College London

Degree Specialism: Computational Simulations

Experience in Finance, Politics, Media, Comms

Professional Training: Makers Academy

Passions: functional programming, devops, Linux

Background

I have been programming since I was 13 - building web MMORPGs with friends (HTML & PHP) with 1000s of players. At university (2:1 Physics) I spent 2 years programming a bio-ecosystem simulation (C++). I have worked in politics, film production, TV & theatre development, and finance. I pushed and built tech solutions in all of these industries from simple web apps (Node, Python, Ruby), to finance analysis apps (Java). I trained myself at a top dev bootcamp, focussing on professional full-stack skills and modern methodologies.

Recently at HSBC, our small team brought modern disciplines to a heavily regulated corporate environment. We demonstrated the benefits of devops, agile, continuous delivery, microservice architectures, constant retrospection and developer freedom, whilst always focussing on releasing value to clients.

Skills

Programming:

- JavaScript (ES6, Node, Express, Dojo, JQuery, RxJS, Selenium) 6+ yrs
- Clojure (Compojure) 1+ yrs
- Java (Android, Spring) 2+ yrs
- Ruby (Rails) 1yr
- C++ 3+ yrs
- Python
- HTML, HTML5, CSS, LESS
- DB (MySQL PostgreSQL, Mongo)

Delivery/Ops:

- Continuous Delivery (Jenkins, TeamCity, Heroku)
- · Version control: Git. RTC
- Linux (Redhat, Debian, Ubuntu)
- Bash
- Networking (DNS, TCP/IP, HTTPS)
- Eclipse, IntelliJ, Android Studio (though I MVC Architectures prefer a text editor where possible)

Methodologies:

- Devops (Fast release cycles)
- Agile (lots of retrospecting)
- Test Driven Development
- Behaviour Driven Development
- Pairing
- Microservices Architectures

Other Expertise

Government: I have 8 years experience across Government, public policy, and the digital & creative industries. I continue to support a political network for those sector.

Finance: Aside from my work in HSBC's FX department, I have also worked in a credit trading hedge fund, a Chinese event-driven brokerage, and a corporate finance boutique (analysing media and tech opportunities).

Communications: I have worked on public policy campaigns, political communications, and film & theatre marketing. I have written newspaper articles, press releases, and organised political conferences.

Work History

HSBC GFX (Dec 2016 - Sept 2017) | DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

We delivered a suite of microservices in Clojure and ES6 and interfacing them with a legacy Java6 / dojo.js monolith.

Our team of 6 worked from within the modernising agile-embracing GFX department of the investment bank, but worked to bring their products into HSBCnet, one of the world's most used commercial payment applications.

I worked in a mordern coding environment: devops, daily release cycles, developer anarchy, microservices, test-driven development and client behaviour driven development, with an ability to write code and have it in production in the same day. However I simultaneously worked on the HSBCnet application, being developed on a quarterly release cycle, with manual testing, and old SDLCs.

Makers Consultants (Dec 2016 - Present) | SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CONSULTANT

I was involved from the beginning in Makers Academy's Consultancy arm. I have remit to work on Makers' educationbased platform when not with a corporate partners (HSBC, Tek Systems, & Allegis Group).

Bob & Co (Nov 2014 - May 2016) | HEAD OF DIGITAL AND COMMUNICATIONS

A small media (film, TV, theatre) developer, and financier. I ran the technological, research & communication efforts. I also built (and maintained) the company website, and other applications (Java & JS) for their partners & subsidiaries.

I later became Acting Director of Operations during a staff maternity leave, tasked with extensive audit and efficiency efforts in the IT, telecoms, and other office admin budgets.

SUMS Film & Media (Aug 2015 - Dec 2015) | DIGITAL & TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

An independent film producer. I advised the chief executive on their projects' digital strategies (see IMDB). I worked on various applications, including marketing websites (PHP & HTML5).

North Square Blue Oak (Jan 2014 - Mar 2014) | SABBATICAL ANALYST

A brokerage and corporate finance boutique, assessing new corporate finance opportunities in the digital sectors. The company drew heavily on my technological expertise in assessing potential investments.

CQS Asset Management (Feb 2013 - Mar 2013) | MARGINS DEPT ANALYST & DEVELOPMENT INTERN

A \$13bn credit hedge fund: in liability management analysis with collateral specialists (creating an app to assess marginal risks); and also with the strategic IT team, developing a credit price monitor application (C#).

Office of the Digital & Cultural Minister (Nov 2008 - Nov 2014) | SENIOR PARLIAMENTARY ADVISOR

I managed the Parliamentary office of Rt. Hon. Ed Vaizey MP from the date of his Ministerial appointment. I oversaw the running of the office, interviewing, training and managing all junior staff. I worked on campaigns such as improving Wifi provision in public libraries and bringing coding into the national curriculum.

Aside from working on digital & media policy, I was given a wide remit and free-reign within the office, so I often used programmed office solutions, developing wordpress applications (*PHP*) for websites and databasing, and MS access applications for automating emails and training.

Education

Makers Academy (May 2016 - Aug 2016)

Makers Academy afforded me the opportunity to learn professional best practices, surrounded by some truly great programmers. I developed my curiosity and hungry passion for code, with focus on becoming an independent learner and problem-solver. They offer a firm grounding in the principles of software craftsmanship: OOP, TDD, SOLID, BDD.

Physics 2:1 (BSc & ARCS): Imperial College London (Oct 2005 - July 2008)

I focussed on computational simulations, astrophysics, plasma physics, and the practicalities of nuclear fusion energy as a future energy source.

Final Year Degree Project (C++)

I received 93% for an computer simulation investigation into the process of evolution. I wrote the program from scratch, modelling biological systems. I was praised particularly for analysing great amounts of data, spotting patterns and anomalies, presenting them accessibly and quantifying the results in a manner that the department had never seen before.

Interests

CACIN - The Political Creative Industries Network (2008 - 2017) | DIRECTOR

I developed and maintained relationships with many key players in the tech & creative sectors, and ran regular panels and drinks receptions across the UK, centering on issues from the digital single market to diversity in the media.

The Digital Bazaar, Tate South Lambeth Library (2009 - 2013) | FOUNDING VOLUNTEER & IT EXPERT Taught basic computer, smartphone and other technology use to struggling members of the Lambeth community (many of whom did not have English as a first language). Runners-up for the CILIP Libraries Change Lives Award 2012.

Other:

Tech Tinkering – I'm a Linux user at home (Fedora, Debian, Ubuntu, Mint). I have a home-made NAS made with a Raspberry Pi, and a homemade server – also running on Raspbian. I code small apps (usually in ES6 now) and run them from that server.

Music - I have an extensively musical education. I received the music scholarship to my secondary school. I sang in a Christ Church Cathedral Choir Oxford, and played the Saxophone, Violin, Piano, and guitar.

Tennis - I play regularly with a variety of partners and am coached professionally.

Cooking - I love cooking and spend a great deal of time in the kitchen. My recipes are popular on Instagram.